colescareers.com.au 2019-03-05

# 

Date: November 2018

**1\. Overview**

At Coles, we respect the privacy of your personal information in our care. Your privacy is very important to us.

Personal Information means information which identifies you as an individual or from which you can be reasonably identified. This statement tells you in general terms what our commitment is for recruitment-related information: why we need to collect personal information, what personal information we collect, how we handle it and who we may disclose it to (outside of Coles). We also collect personal information from you when you are a customer. The Coles Privacy Policy found at [www.coles.com.au/privacy](http://coles.com.au/privacy) covers our handling of personal information of our customers.

**2\. Types of Personal Information Collected**

During the recruitment process we will collect personal information (including sensitive information) about you which may include, but is not limited, to items such as:

  * Your name;
  * Date of birth;
  * Email address;
  * Phone number;
  * Contact details;
  * Employment history;
  * Education qualifications;
  * Professional licenses, and memberships of professional associations;
  * Referee details and reference notes;
  * Results of aptitude and psychometric tests;
  * Right to work checking (visa, passport information) and security checks;
  * Video interviews; and
  * Medical and police checks.

Where you provide us with Personal Information about someone else, you must have their consent to provide their Personal Information to us based on this Privacy Policy.

**3\. How Personal Information is collected and held**

Your personal information (including sensitive information) will be collected via your application form, CV and covering letter, recruitment agency reports during interviews and telephone calls, written correspondence and sometimes from publicly available sources such as LinkedIn or other social media sites.

We may also collect information from third parties such as when we carry out background and probity checks and when we collect references. These third parties may have their own privacy policies that address how they handle personal Information.

If you choose not to provide certain personal information, we may not be able to progress your application, or provide you with direct correspondence regarding employment opportunities at Coles.

You might also need to provide personal information about other individuals to us (e.g. your referee contact details). If so, we rely on you to inform those individuals that you are providing their personal information to us and to advise them of the matters in this Privacy Policy.

Your personal information and application information will be used to assist us throughout the recruitment process. We may use your personal information to verify your identity and for other purposes such as contacting referees or performing background checks.

We retain personal information we collect about applicants, prospective applicants and previous Coles team members in our Applicant Tracking System (ATS) and other databases. If we include your details in our ATS and other databases, we can assess your potential suitability for future job opportunities. We may be in touch from time to time to make sure your contact details are up to date and to let you know about opportunities with Coles that may be of interest to you. You may contact us at any time if this is no longer of interest to you.

We hold Personal Information electronically and in hard copy form, both at our own premises and with the assistance of our service providers. We implement a range of measures, including people, process and technology controls, to protect the security of your Personal Information. Examples of these measures include:

  * Access to Personal Information is controlled through access and identity management systems;
  * Coles Team members, and agents acting on our behalf, are bound by internal information security policies and are required to keep Personal Information secure at all times;
  * We take steps to protect Personal Information in accordance with the Office of the Information Commissioner’s Guide to Securing Personal Information; and
  * We also take measures in respect of destroying or de-identifying Personal Information that is no longer needed for any lawful purpose.

Our security controls are continually reviewed to ensure that the protection of your Personal Information is maintained.

**4\. Purposes for Handling and Sharing Personal Information**

The Candidate and Team Members’ PI Coles collects may only be used for the particular purpose for which it is required, or for directly related purposes, which may include determining eligibility for initial employment, including the verification of references and qualifications. We may disclose your Personal Information to recruiters and Coles Team Members who are involved in our hiring process. Your Personal Information may also be shared with recruitment agencies and other third parties who are engaged to provide recruitment services on our behalf.

Some of the technology service providers that hold and process Candidate and Team Members’ PI may have data centres located outside Australia. While it is not reasonably practicable to list all countries to which your Personal Information may be disclosed from time to time, it is likely that such countries may include the Germany, New Zealand, the Philippines, Singapore, and the United States.

When we disclose your information overseas, we take steps to ensure that our technology service providers are obliged to protect the privacy and security of your Personal Information in accordance to the standards that apply in Australia, including that they only use Personal Information for the purpose for which is it disclosed.

Where you provide us with Personal Information about someone else, you must have their consent to provide their Personal Information to us based on this Privacy Policy.

**5\. Procedures for access to or correction of your personal information**

You agree to provide your Personal Information, which is in all respects true, accurate and up to date and is not, in any respect, misleading, deceptive or inaccurate or likely to be misleading or deceptive.

If you wish to access or correct any Personal Information we hold about you, please contact us as set out below.

When making an access request, please provide as much detail as you can about the particular information you seek, in order to help us retrieve it. Under the Privacy Act and other relevant laws, we are required to provide a written response outlining our reasons if we refuse your request.

Where we decide not to make a requested correction and you disagree, you may ask us to add a note of your requested correction to the information that explains your correction request. You are encouraged to help us keep your Personal Information accurate, complete, and up-to-date by updating your profile on our Coles careers website when applying for an advertised vacancy, or when updating your expression of interest registration preferences.

Please contact us at [careers@coles.com.au](mailto:careers@coles.com.au) if you think there is something wrong with the information we hold about you and we'll try to correct it. If you are not satisfied with their response, please contact the Privacy Officer at  [privacy@coles.com.au](mailto:privacy@coles.com.au.).

If you are still not satisfied, you can contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner, whose contact details are set out below. We'll try and help where we can - if we can't, then we'll let you know in writing.

**6\. Complaints and concerns**

If you have any complaints or concerns about this Policy, or our handling of your Personal Information, you can contact us as set out below. The Privacy Officer will oversee the management of any complaint and be in contact with you within 30 days of receipt of your complaint.

Once a complaint has been lodged, we will let you know who will be handling your matter and when you can expect a full response within 30 days. If you are not satisfied with our response, please let us know and we will investigate further and respond to you.

If you are still not satisfied, you can contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner, whose contact details are set out below.

**Contact Details**

Queries regarding privacy should be directed to the Coles Privacy Officer:

Phone: 1800 061 562

Email: [privacy@coles.com.au](mailto:privacy@coles.com.au)

Post: 800 Toorak Road, Hawthorn East VIC 3123

**Office of the Australian Information Commissioner**

GPO Box 5218 Sydney NSW 2001

Telephone: 1300 363 992

Email: [enquiries@oaic.gov.au](mailto:enquiries@oaic.gov.au)

Website: [www.oaic.gov.au](http://www.oaic.gov.au/)

Back to top
